teachstarter.com 2019-12-09

# Teach Starter Privacy Policy

## 1\. Privacy Policy

Teach Starter Pty Ltd ABN 69 634 768 817 ( **Teach Starter** ) takes all reasonable steps to implement processes and procedures to safeguard Personal Information.  Teach Starter endeavours to but is not required to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles contained in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) ( **Law** ).  While not claiming to be a statement of compliance, this Privacy Policy outlines Teach Starter’s use, collection and storage of Personal Information.

This Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Information collected by Teach Starter in the course of providing services to users ( **Users** ) regardless of the source of that Personal Information.  This Privacy Policy is available on the Site.

This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with Teach Starter’s [**Terms and Conditions**](https://www.teachstarter.com/about/terms-and-conditions/ "Terms & Conditions") when using the Site and interacting with Teach Starter.

### 1.1 Definitions

Terms that are capitalised in this Privacy Policy are defined below, unless the context indicates otherwise:

**Site** means www.teachstarter.com

**Minor** means a person under the age of eighteen (18).

**Personal Information** means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

(a)           whether the information or opinion is true or not; and

(b)           whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

**Privacy Policy** means this privacy policy and amendments made to it.

## 2\. Obligations under the Law

### 2.1 Collection of Personal Information

Teach Starter collects Personal Information about Users in order to provide the Users with the services and goods they have requested.  If this information is not provided Teach Starter may not be able to provide Users with requested services or goods.

**Teach Starter endeavours to collect Personal Information from Users directly.   Information Teach Starter obtains from third parties or publically available information is limited to circumstances where the User has consented whether expressly or impliedly.**

### 2.2 Types of Personal Information collected

Personal Information Teach Starter collects may include a person’s first and last names and email address and any other Personal Information supplied by the User.  If a User connects Teach Starter to a third party social media service, Teach Starter may collect additional Personal Information that includes social media profile handles, user ID and/or user names associated with that service and any information or content the User has permitted the social media service to share with Teach Starter, which may include the User’s profile picture, email address, friends or follower lists, and information the User has disclosed in connection with that social media services.

### 2.3 Sensitive information

Teach Starter does not collect sensitive information about Users.  Sensitive information includes information about racial or ethnic origin; or political opinions; or membership of a political association; or religious beliefs or affiliations; or philosophical beliefs; or membership of a professional or trade association; or membership of a trade union; or sexual orientation or practices; or criminal record; that is also personal information; or health information about an individual; or genetic information about an individual that is not otherwise health information; or biometric information that is to be used for the purpose of automated biometric verification or biometric identification; or biometric templates.

### 2.4 Purpose of collection and use

Teach Starter collects, holds, uses and discloses Personal Information to deliver and improve the goods or services Teach Starter provides to Users.  Generally, Users are only obliged to provide Teach Starter with information necessary for Teach Starter to provide services to the User.  However, if Users do not provide Teach Starter with certain types of Personal Information Teach Starter may be unable to provide the User the services or goods they have requested.

### 2.5 Collection of information from the Internet

Teach Starter collects information from the Site and from Teach Starter’s interactions with the Users.  This information is all held in digital format only.

The programs and applications Teach Starter use are password protected and encrypted. Reasonable steps are taken to ensure all information provided is secure.  Teach Starter will collect Personal Information by only lawful and fair means.  The Law requires Teach Starter to collect Personal Information about Users from the Users directly, if it is reasonable and practical to do so.

## 3\. Access, correction and complaint procedure

### 3.1 Accessing Personal Information about you

If a User would like to access or correct Personal Information that Teach Starter holds about them, please contact:  
**The Privacy Officer**

Scott Tonges

Teach Starter Pty Ltd ABN 69 634 768 817  
Level 2, 55 Railway Terrace  
Milton, QLD 4064  
Australia

Telephone: 1800 790 441

Email: support@teachstarter.com

The User will need to identify themselves to the reasonable satisfaction of Teach Starter before Teach Starter will provide the User with their Personal Information which Teach Starter may or may not have in its possession.

### 3.2 Complaints procedure

Teach Starter operates a service orientated business via the Site.  If a User has a complaint about Teach Starter’s collection or use of Personal Information pertaining to that User, then the User is requested to contact Teach Starter’s **Privacy Officer** at first instance.

If after investigating the User’s complaint and reporting to the User about an alleged breach of the Australian Privacy Principles and reporting the results of Teach Starter’s investigations to the User, the User is not satisfied, then Teach Starter requests that the User consult:

**The Australian Information Privacy Commissioner**

GPO Box 5218  
Sydney  NSW  2001  
Telephone: 1300 363 992

Email: enquiries@oaic.gov.au

A complaint form can be found at: https://forms.business.gov.au/aba/oaic/privacy-complaint-/

### 3.3 Transfer of Personal Information outside Australia

Personal Information Teach Starter collects may in the future be accessed by employees and contractors of service providers outside of Australia.  Personal Information may be transferred to countries outside Australia including but not limited to Singapore.

Teach Starter takes reasonable steps to ensure that parties that provide Teach Starter with necessary services for website hosting and database administration act in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles and have signed undertakings for their staff relating to confidentiality.  Teach Starter also uses only recognised service providers who use enterprise level software with up to date SSL Encryption.

### 3.4 Anonymity and use of pseudonyms

Where practical and reasonable to do so, Teach Starter provides Users with the opportunity to use pseudonyms in relation to information Users provide to Teach Starter.  Where appropriate Teach Starter will provide Users with the option in interact anonymously.

### 3.5 How Teach Starter deals with unsolicited Personal Information

Teach Starter only collects Personal Information about individuals by lawful and fair means.

### 3.6 Notice of collection of Personal Information

Where possible, Teach Starter notifies the Users when Teach Starter is collecting Personal Information about the Users, use of which is subject to this Privacy Policy.

**Collection Notice**

By providing Teach Starter with this information, the User acknowledges that Teach Starter is collecting and storing Personal Information about the User.  Teach Starter does this only for the purpose of providing goods or services to the User.

## 4\. Use of Personal Information in Direct Marketing

### 4.1 Direct marketing

Teach Starter may use Personal Information for the purposes of promoting goods or services to Users where they would reasonably expect it to be used for this purpose.  If Teach Starter uses a User’s Personal Information to provide them with promotional and marketing information Teach Starter will provide the User with an option to opt out of this service.  Teach Starter does not provide goods that contain advertising targeted towards Minors.

### 4.2 Opting out

Users can unsubscribe to Teach Starter’s newsletters or marketing material by clicking on the functional unsubscribe facility contained in any email or by contacting The Privacy Officer on the details set out above.

### 4.3 Use of Cookies

Teach Starter collects Personal Information that is reasonably necessary for the performance of Teach Starter’s operations and activities including marketing and sales.  Teach Starter automatically receives and records information on its server logs from the User’s browser, including their IP address, operating system, top level domain, date and time, pages accessed, documents downloaded, previous website visited, type of browser used and other cookie information.  This enables Teach Starter to tell when Users use the Site and also to help customise the User’s experience within the Site.  No Personal Information about a User is linked to the cookie nor is there any data matching between cookie information and User’s internet activity.

## 5\. Integrity of Personal Information

### 5.1 Security measures taken for Personal Information

Teach Starter takes reasonable steps to protect the Personal Information Teach Starter holds from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure when Teach Starter sends Personal Information offshore.  Further, Teach Starter takes reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify Personal Information if it is no longer needed for the purpose it was collected.

### 5.2 Accuracy

Teach Starter takes reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information Teach Starter collects, uses or discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

### 5.3 Security

Teach Starter takes reasonable steps to safeguard the disclosure of Personal Information from third parties, contractors and staff.  Teach Starter has up to date procedures and policies relating to information technology as it relates to staff and strive for best practice in this area.

## 6\. Changes to Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time.  The current version is available on the Site.  This policy was last updated on 9 July 2014.
